Javascript Developer | Data Scientist

maneldje81@gmail.com +213 0552230871 Bab Ezzouar, Algiers, 16042, Algeria

Date / Place of birth 25-09-1997 / Algiers

Driving license Yes

Nationality

Algerian

Manel Djehiche

Profile

I am principally a JavaScript Web Developer with 5 years of experience and a Data Scientist using python with 3 years of experience, I worked with many other technologies like Java, C++, and PHP.

For web development, I am a back-end and front-end programmer using NodeJs and ReactJs having the knowledge to choose the best conception of the database [relational or no relational].

Speaking about Artificial intelligence, I have a good level in Deep learning, Nlp, Machine learning, problem resolution, problem optimization, and data mining. I can do data collection and data cleaning, and then build models that help you taking the right decision.

I have worked in many companies which allows me to get strong expertise in team-working, social intelligence, problem resolution, how to discuss the functionalities with the customer, reporting, and choosing the best technologies in order to get the best results possible.

My latest job is as a full stack web developer in Sonelgaz company, it's an international Algerian company that is responsible for sharing the electricity and the gas in all the country, that gave me a good experience in graphs and how to treat complicated problems with high complexity.

Employment History

Full stack web developer at Dz-Canada [Remote - CD], Québec

07/2018-12/2018

- Creation of dynamic web application using PHP, MySQL,
- Customizing HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP AND REACT templates depending the the need of the client.
- Building E-commerce websites using OpenCART.

Full Stack Javascript Developer at LAKKINI [CD], Algeria

04/2021-11/2022

- I used to create Restful API using Nodejs, MongoDB on the server-side.
- On the client-side using REACT, HTML, CSS.

Microservices with Golang & React developer at Emplorium [Remote - CD], London

06/2022-12/2022

Links

<u>Linkdin</u> <u>Github Projects</u>

- I used to create GraphQL API using Golang, Postgres.
- On the client-side, working with React.
- Handling microservices architecture and how to define multiple services.

Javascript Web developer at Elit Sonelgaz [CI], Algiers

12/2021—Present

- Handling graphs and high complexity networks.
- Real problem resolution and optimization.
- Back-end using NodeJs and python.
- Front-end using ReactJs.

Deep Learning and Machine Learning developer at Freelance tasks

04/2020-Present

I used to take projects in AI using machine learning and deep learning tools.

- Data collection using web scraping from websites.
- Cleaning data and preparing it for machine learning.
- Creating smart models with TensorFlow, Sklearn, Pandas, and Keras Libraries with Python.

Education

Master 2 in Artificial Intelligence, University of Science and Technology Houari Boumediene, Algiers

09/2018-06/2020

I have got huge expertise in Artificial intelligence from my university in different domains, including data mining, vision computer, NLP, problem resolution, algorithm optimization, and complexity.

Licence in computer systems, University of algiers, Algiers

09/2015-06/2018

I have learned many things related to web development and database structure, including MySQL database, UML for conception, How to choose the best architecture for database related to the problem, web application, understanding very well how processors and pcs work which allows me to know what data structure to choose in my programs and algorithm.

Internships

Deep Learning Researcher at RESEARCH CENTRE FOR SCIENTIFIC AND TECHNICAL INFORMATION, Algiers

Skills

PHP

CSS

HTML5

SQL

jQuery

MySQL

MongoDB

Git

Python

Java

HTML & CSS

Node.js

Conflict Resolution

React

JavaScript

Typescript

AJAX

Postgres

Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas and SKlearn

Golang

Languages

English	Highly proficient
French	Highly proficient
Arabic	Native speaker

Courses

ReactJs at Zero to Hero Academy

Deep Learnin in NLP at Coursera

Machine Learning at Coursera

English at Royal School

Senior Web Developer at Zero to Hero Academy

Natural Language Processing at Coursera

01/2020-06/2020

I have built multiple deep learning and machine learning models in the project "Sentiment Analysis Algerian Dialect". I went through different steps, let me resume them for you.

- Data Collection from Facebook
- Having done deep research of related works then I have invented my own solution by contributing to the subject of 'Sentiment Analysis Arabic Dialect'
- · Data cleaning
- Implementing common models of deep learning and machine learning then proposing my own model by combining different models, then comparing different architecture

Resolution of communication problem between two applications using Web Service at General Directorate of Douane, Algiers

01/2018-06/2018

I have created a web service that automatically allows data exchange between two websites using Java, MySQL, and Bootstrap.

Participation in Chatbot system at Emplorium

08/2021-12/2021

I have participated in a chatbot website that allows communication with customers.

- · Creation of multiples agents accounts.
- A customer can ask any question in the chat.
- Each agent can answer customers' questions. So agents between them work at the same time without any problem.

Participation in School management system at Lakkini

- 1- Communication with the School director to get functionalities.
- 2- Restful API on the server side using NodeJs and MongoDB.
- 3- JavaScript Framework on the client site [Ajax, Query]